Guide to the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America records, 1914-1980.
Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America records, 1914-1980.
- VII. Sidney Hillman papers, 1930-1946. (Box 66-111)
  - A. Correspondence, 1930-46.
    - Labor Defender, 1935-43 (Box 76, Folder 22)
    - Labor (U.S. Department of) correspondence with the Labor Department's administrative staff (Frances Perkins letters are filed separately) concerning child labor, minimum wage, Walsh Healey Act, old age security, textile workers organizing drive and unemployment insurance, 1935-41 (Box 76, Folder 23-28)
    - Labor Housing Forum, 1935 (Box 76, Folder 29)
    - Labor News Service, 1935 (Box 76, Folder 30)
    - Labor's Non-Partisan League (1936-40) correspondence with George Berry (President), E.L. Oliver, (Vice-President) and other League officers, includes 1936 Declaration of Principles. (Box 77, Folder 1-7)
    - Labor Organization (International) 1937 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Labor Press Associates, 1940 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Labor Stage (Louis Schaffer) 1937, Includes copy of a review of "Steel". (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Ladies Garment Workers Union (International) 1934 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Ladies' Handbag, Pocketbook and Novelty Workers Union, 1941 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - LaFollette, Phillip (Governor of Wisconsin) 1936-38 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - LaFollette, Robert (Senator from Wisconsin) 1930-37 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - LaGuardia, Fiorello (Mayor of New York) 1930-41, Includes memo for the President from "the Committee", Office of Civilian Defense, recommending the President issue an Order forbidding discrimination based on race, color or creed in Government offices, as well as the incorporation of a "no discrimination" clause into defense contracts (1941). (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Laidler, Harry (League for Industrial Democracy) 1930-36 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Lake County (Illinois) Labor Council 1937 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Lamneck, A.P. (Congressman from Ohio) 1935 (Box 77, Folder 18)
    - Landau, Abraham (Julius Schwartz and Sons Clothing Manufacturers) 1941 (Box 77, Folder 19)
    - Landon, Samuel, Local 98, Philadelphia, 1932 (Box 77, Folder 20)
    - Lang, Fannie (Organizer, Cincinnati) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 21)
    - Lash, Joseph (Student League for Industrial Democracy) 1935-40 (Box 77, Folder 22)
    - Lasnick, William (Morristown, Tennessee Clothing Worker) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 23)
    - Lauck, William Jett (Economist, UMW and CIO) 1937-38, Includes correspondence relating to National Conference on Constitutional Amendment; the American Association For Economic Freedom's defense of the Wagner Act and the National Labor Relations Board. (Box 77, Folder 24)
    - Laundry Owners Association of New York, 1938-40 (Box 77, Folder 25)
    - Laundry Workers Joint Board, 1937-42 (Box 77, Folder 26)
    - Lawson, John C. (Quarry Workers' International Union) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 27)
    - Lawton, S.J. (National Association for Taxation of Labor Displacing Devices) 1935 (Box 77, Folder 28)
    - Leach, Henry (Forum) 1936-37, Includes "Do High Wages Make Prosperity? Two Points of View on Permanent Recovery" by Irving Fisher and Edward A. Filene; "John L. Lewis' Push to Power" by Louis Adamic. (Box 77, Folder 29)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1938 (Box 77, Folder 30)
    - League for Labor Palestine, 1934 (Box 77, Folder 31)
    - League of Nations Association, 1938 (Box 77, Folder 32)
    - League for Political Education, 1935 (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Leather Workers Association, 1936 (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Leather Workers Union (United) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Lehman, Herbert (Governor of NY) 1928-40, ALP endorsement; aid to education; aid to war sufferers and refugees overseas. (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Leiserson, William (National Mediation Board) 1936, Personal correspondence relating to Ruth Leiserson (daughter of William) and Philoine Hillman; possible recommendation of Gus Peck to the maritime industry's mediation board. (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Lerman, Frank (Boston Joint Board) 1940 (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Leventhal, Henry Inc. (Boston Manufacturer) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Levin, Lawrence (regarding the Equal Rights Amendment) 1942, Includes Josephine Casey's (Field Worker, National Woman's Party) discussion of night work laws for women in "A Fair Labor Standard". (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - Levin, Samuel (Chicago Joint Board) 1935-40 (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Levinson, Morris (Los Angeles Clothing Worker) 1939 (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Levy, Joseph (Crawford Clothes) 1938-41 (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Levy, Matthew (Judge, NYC) 1938 (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Levy, Samuel, 1941, Includes a letter from Isaac Herzog (Chief Rabbi of The Holy Land). (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Lewis, A.D. (UMW) 1937, Contains a reference to the Anderson investigation by the LaFollette Civil Liberties Committee and the "Harlan County situation". (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - Lewis, A.T. (ACWA organizer, Norfolk, Va.) n.d. (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Lewis, John L. (UMW and CIO) 1935-40, Correspondence documenting the organization of the CIO and its jurisdictional disputes with the AFL. Significant correspondence from John L. Lewis and President Franklin D. Roosevelt, concerning violations of the NLRA, as well as NLRB orders, by corporations under government contracts; Hillman's selection of members of the Labor Policy Advisory Committee, and James J. Matles' (Director of Organization, United Electrical, Radio & Machine Workers of America) contention that his industry was excluded from the Committee because it was "tinged with `Red'" (7/22/40); Donald Sham's (Professor of Economics, University of Santa Clara) explanation of how the United States Postal Saving System serves workers, and bankers' organized opposition to this system (11/14/36). (Box 78, Folder 1-5)
    - Lewis, Sinclair (author) 1930 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Licastro, Philip (Organizer, Syracuse) 1940 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Lieberman, Elias (attorney, regarding NRA labor standards and the Child Labor Amendment) 1935-37 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Liebowitz, Max J. (ACWA attorney, New York, N.Y.) 1937 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Liberty League, 1935-36 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Liepold, Karl (Clothing Worker, fired because he ran for sheriff. Atchinson, Kansas 1934) (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Lincoln Brigade (Friends of the) 1938, Correspondence relating to the rehabilitation of American volunteers. (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Lippman, Walter, 1940, Hillman's criticism of Lippman's "`Total Defense' -Minus". (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Lischinsky, S.A. (ACWA Wage and Hour Bureau) 1939-40, Correspondence relating to a complaint against the Sun Manufacturing Company of St. Joseph, Missouri. (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Lithuanian Jews (Farband of) (in Hebrew) 1938 (Box 78, Folder 15)
    - Lodge, Henry Cabot (Senator) 1937, Includes S.28 (regarding a national unemployment census) (Box 78, Folder 16)
    - Loeb, Philip, 1940 (Box 78, Folder 17)
    - Lord, James (UMW) 1934, Letter reflects Lord's interpretation of President Roosevelt's attitude toward organized labor. (Box 78, Folder 18)
    - Lore, Ludwig, (author) 1938, 40 (Box 78, Folder 19)
    - Los Angeles Central Labor Council, 1935, Correspondence concerning an FCC permit "to establish a Radio Broadcasting Station in East Los Angeles, to be known as `The Voice of Organized Labor'". (Box 78, Folder 20)
    - Los Angeles City Council, 1943 (Box 78, Folder 21)
    - Lovestone, Jay (Workers Age) 1937-38, Request for Hillman to appeal to Juan Negrin (President of Spain) on behalf of Republic of Spain. (Box 78, Folder 22)
    - Lowenberg, Henry A. (attorney), 1936-38, Support for the ALP; Are Taxes Necessary (5pp). (Box 78, Folder 23)
    - Lowenthal, Max (Senate Committee on Commerce) 1936-38 (Box 78, Folder 24)
    - Lorwin, Lewis (International Labour Office, Geneva) 1938 (Box 78, Folder 25)
    - Lubell, Bros. (N.Y. clothing manufacturer) 1935-38 (Box 78, Folder 26)
    - Lund, R. (clothing worker) 1938 (Box 78, Folder 27)
    - Lundeen, Ernest (Senator Minn.) 1936-38, S. 1463 (the American Youth Act) (Box 78, Folder 28)
    - Lyons, John, 1935-37 (Box 78, Folder 29)
    - L (general) 1929-42, Correspondence includes discussion of low-cost housing (7pp) forwarded by Bruno Lasker; S.C Lamport's (President, The Lamport Export Company) address before the Export Managers Club, "The Russian Market" (7pp); Seymour B. Liebman's (attorney) efforts to ensure Joseph C. Baldwin's (Republican, New York State Senator) defeat in the '36 senatorial election; letters suggesting Charles D. Schwartz (attorney) be appointed to a Federal judgeship in Illinois; Arthur M. Lamport's (A.M. Lamport & Company Investment Bonds) radio address "Taylor, Sloan and Lewis (Taxes)" (8pp); the Honorary Committee to welcome Lotte Lehmann (operatic singer) to the United States; the discharge and reinstatement of William Davis at American Viscose Corporation (Lewistown, Penn.); James L. Kilgallen's (staff correspondent, International News Service) report on AFL, CIO conflict, as well as a discussion of Hillman's relationships with President Roosevelt and John L. Lewis. (Box 78, Folder 30-34)
    - McAnally (Iowa Federation of Labor) 1935 (Box 78, Folder 35)
    - McCallister, Frank (Workers Defense League) 1940, Recommends libel suit against the Ku Klux Klan (contains excerpt from "The Fiery Cross"). (Box 78, Folder 36)
    - McCarthy, Frank (Iowa Union Labor Review) 1939 (Box 78, Folder 37)
    - McClellan, John (Senator, Arkansas) 1935, W. E. Carson's (Manager, Carson's Store) discussion of the "differential provision" in the General Code for Wholesale Trade. (Box 78, Folder 38)
    - McConnell, Donald (Conference on Pan American Democracy) 1932-38 (Box 78, Folder 39)
    - McConnell, Bishop Francis (Joint Committee on Unemployment and American Relief Ship to Spain) 1932-38 (Box 78, Folder 40)
    - McCormack, John (Senator, Mass.) 1941 (Box 78, Folder 41)
    - McFadden, Jack (U.C.A.P.A.W.A. Local 30, Yuma, Arizona) 1935 (Box 78, Folder 42)
    - McGinley, Charles (Oil Workers' Union Local 412, Monahans, Texas) 1940, Open letter to the Rank and File criticizing the labor policies of their International. (Box 78, Folder 43)
    - Machine Tool Builders Association of Cleveland, 1938 (Box 78, Folder 44)
    - Machine, Tool and Die Local #155 (Philadelphia) Resolution re CIO, n.d. (Box 78, Folder 45)
    - Machinists (International Association of) 1936-40 (Box 78, Folder 46)
    - MacIntyre, M.H. (Secretary of President Roosevelt) 1938, The wages and hours bill. (Box 78, Folder 47)
    - McKellar, Kenneth (Senator, Tenn.) 1938 (Box 78, Folder 48)
    - McMahon, Thomas (United Textile Workers of America) 1935-39 (Box 78, Folder 49)
    - MacNamara, Gerald (re Fortune article on unemployment) 1939-40 (Box 78, Folder 50)
    - MacNamara, John (President, International Brotherhood of Firemen, Oilers, Helpers, Roundhouse and Railway Ship Laborers) 1935 (Box 78, Folder 51)
    - McNamara, J.B. (San Quentin prisoner) 1931 (Box 78, Folder 52)
    - Macy Chapter of the Dept. Store Organizing Committee, 1937 (Box 78, Folder 53)
    - Macy, R.H., 1937, Memorandum of Agreement between R.H. Macy & Co., Inc., and the Department Stores Organizing Committee, C.I.O. and the Macy Chapter of the Department Stores Organizing Committee, C.I.O. (15pp). (Box 78, Folder 54)
    - Magnusson, Leifur (League of Nations, ILO) 1932-37 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Management (Society for the Advancement of) 1938 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Manhattan Merchant Tailors Association, 1936-37 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Marcantonio, Vito (Congressman, NYC) 1935-40, Wage and Hour Administration. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Margolies, Frank (Vest Makers Local 22, NYC) 1937 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Margoshes, S. (The Day) 1930 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Marine and Shipbuilding Workers (Industrial Union of) 1936-41 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Markewich and Null (ACWA lawyers, concerning Macy's organizing drive) 1938 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - Marsh, Benjamin (People's Lobby) 1936-39 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - Marshall Field and Company, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Marshall, L.S. (Refrigerating Machine Association) 1935 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Martin, Harry (Allied Printing Trade Council) 1935 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Martin, Homer (United Automobile Workers) 1936-38, Aid to General Motors strikers at Fisher-Body plants in Flint; Resolution on International autonomy (relates to Communist faction of the UAW). (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Martinsberg, (West Virginia) Central Labor Union, 1937 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Massillon (Ohio) Trades and Labor Assembly, 1935 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Mason, Lucy (Textile Workers Organizing Committee) 1936-40, Recommendation that the FBI investigate beatings of TWOC staff members in Georgia; memorandum on Washington Manufacturing Company, Nashville, Tennessee, and its successor organizations in their fight against the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America (3pp); "Recent Books and Articles About Labor Unions and Labor Laws" (annotated bibliography); discussion of CIO progress in the South, (with attention to the press's attitude toward the organization). (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Mathews, Joseph, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Matles, James (United Electrical Workers) 1938 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Maverick, Maury (Congressman, Texas) 1937-39 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Mayor's (LaGuardia) Business Advisory Council, 1942, Smaller War Plants Corporation: Utilization of Smaller Plants in New York City (10pp). (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Mead, James (Senator, NY) 1940 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Meat Cutters (Amalgamated) 1937, CIO distribution of pamphlets at A.F. of L. meetings. (Box 79, Folder 22)
    - Mechanics Educational Society of America (Matthew Smith) n.d. (Box 79, Folder 23)
    - Mehlman, Fannie, 1942 (Box 79, Folder 24)
    - Meigs, Merrill (War Production Board) 1940-42 (Box 79, Folder 25)
    - Mellen, Joseph (NY attorney) 1932 (Box 79, Folder 26)
    - Mellon, Gay (NY attorney) 1932, Reprint of "Relief Without Taxation" (Box 79, Folder 27)
    - Men's Clothing Industry (Impartial Chairman) 1940 (Box 79, Folder 28)
    - Men's Shirts and Boys Blouse Contractors (Nat'l. Assoc. of) 1935-40 (Box 79, Folder 29)
    - Merchants and Manufacturers Association (Washington, D.C.) 1941 (Box 79, Folder 30)
    - Merchandise Service and Delivery Workers Union, 1935-36 (Box 79, Folder 31)
    - Merrill, Lewis (United Office and Professional Workers) 1937-39 (Box 79, Folder 32)
    - Meyer, Felix and Comp., 1937 (Box 79, Folder 33)
    - Meyer, Max (includes correspondence regarding NRA Code Authority) 1935-40 (Box 79, Folder 34)
    - Meyner, Robert (attorney, N.J.) 1937 (Box 79, Folder 35)
    - Michels, Reuben, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 36)
    - Michelson, Max (St. Louis Joint Board) 1938 (Box 79, Folder 37)
    - Michigan University, 1938 (Box 79, Folder 38)
    - Millinery Union (New York Local 25) 1937 (Box 79, Folder 39)
    - Milton, George F. (historian) 1940 (Box 79, Folder 40)
    - Milwaukee Leader, 1930 (Box 79, Folder 41)
    - Mine, Mill and Smelter Workers (International Union) 1936-40 (Box 79, Folder 42)
    - Mine Workers (United) 1936-41, Granting charters; union publications. (Box 79, Folder 43)
    - Minnesota Conference on Progressive Labor Action, 1936 (Box 79, Folder 44)
    - Minor, Robert (Communist Party, USA) 1935, The Tom Mooney case (Box 79, Folder 45)
    - Modesto Defense Fund (San Francisco International Longshoremen's Union) 1936 (Box 79, Folder 46)
    - Mooney, Dewey (unemployed union man, Kentucky) 1940 (Box 79, Folder 47)
    - Montreal Clothing Contractors Association, 1940 (Box 79, Folder 48)
    - Moody, Blair (Detroit News) 1938 (Box 79, Folder 49)
    - Mooney, Tom (telegram, 1937); Moony and Billings, San Francisco Bay Area A.F. of L. Committee for the Freedom of, 1938 (Box 79, Folder 50)
    - Morey, Robert (1938) concerning open shop campaign (Box 79, Folder 51)
    - Morgenthau, Henry, 1938-41 (Box 79, Folder 52)
    - Morrison, Frank (secretary, AFL) 1934-36, Council for Industrial Progress, Report of Committee on National Industrial Policy (4pp). (Box 79, Folder 53)
    - Morris, Newbold (NYC Councilman) 1936, A local law to establish a body to determine the facts underlying industrial disputes. (Box 79, Folder 54)
    - Mortimer, Wyndham (UAW) 1938, Frank P. Tucci (UAW Regional Director and "a member of the Black Legion") (Box 79, Folder 55)
    - Moskowitz, Henry, 1936-37 (Box 79, Folder 56)
    - Motion Picture Guild, 1940, Request for assistance making a film to popularize the idea that Americans can "keep out of the war if they wish to". (Box 79, Folder 57)
    - Murphy, Frank (Governor of Michigan) 1938-40 (Box 79, Folder 58)
    - Murphy, Robert (United States Political Advisor for Germany) 1945, Russian aid to the Soviet Sector of Berlin. (Box 79, Folder 59)
    - Murray, James (Senate Committee on Small Business) 1942, concerning General Somervell testimony (Box 79, Folder 60)
    - Murray, Philip (Steel Workers Organizing Committee and CIO) 1936-44, Description of "some phases of the primary election campaign in Philadelphia"; Proposal for Effective Use of Available Labor Supply for National Defense; Memorandum regarding Defense Industries Labor Board; An Open Letter to Mr. OPM; Resolution on Political Action. (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Musicians (American Federation of) 1935 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Myers, Howard (NRA Labor Studies Section) 1935 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - M (general) 1930-42, Questionnaire from Angus McDonald (University of Oklahoma) relating to the effects of the NRA on workers; Tom Mooney - Billings case; the motion picture machine operators of New York City; Federal funds for prison factories in Missouri; the effect of "the European War" on Americans enrolled in medical schools in Scotland; An Open Letter to Mr. A. Chatman, Head of the Amalgamated Union, concerning a union loyalty clause; J. L. Magnes' (The Hebrew University), "Palestine and Arab Union"; the Marcantonio Bill (abolition of the poll tax). (Box 80, Folder 4-7)
    - Nachshon, Ltd (Palestine Labor Maritime Committee) 1937 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Nash, A. (Company, Cincinnati) 1937, "... keeping older people in our employ." (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Nathan, Reuben S. (Office of War Production) 1942, A German translation of a Hillman speech. (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Nation, 1936 (Box 80, Folder 11)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (correspondence with Walter White) 1937 (Box 80, Folder 12)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1935 (Box 80, Folder 13)
    - National Citizens Political Action Committee, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 14)
    - National Federation of Post Office Clerks, 1936 (Box 80, Folder 15)
    - National Industrial Conference Board, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 16)
    - National Recovery Administration, 1934-36, "General Code Authority and the Cotton Garment Code Authority situation; Cotton garment compliance machinery; Report from Anna Rosenberg (New York City Office) listing (by company) changes in working conditions, wages, and hours; Leon Kellman's (Assistant Secretary, National Work Shirt Manufacturers Association, Inc.) criticism of the Prison Labor Authority (PLA); consolidation of telegraph companies; minutes of the final meeting of the Labor Authority Board; review of Hardy's book, The Clothing Workers. (Box 80, Folder 17-19)
    - National Labor Committee for Palestine, 1936-37 (Box 80, Folder 20)
    - National Labor Relations Board (regarding controversy over compliance in automobile and ship building industries) 1934-39 (Box 80, Folder 21)
    - National League of Women Voters, 1932 (Box 80, Folder 22)
    - National Negro Congress (correspondence with John Davis) 1937-41, Wage and Hours Act (Box 80, Folder 23)
    - National Policy Committee, 1936-38 (Box 80, Folder 24)
    - National Public Housing Conference (Helen Alfred) 1938 (Box 80, Folder 25)
    - National Resources Planning Board (Office of the President of the U.S.) 1943 (Box 80, Folder 26)
    - National Retail Code Authority (NRA) correspondence with Richard Neustadt, 1935 (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - National War Fund (includes AFL-CIO Memorandum of Understanding) 1943 (Box 80, Folder 28)
    - National Youth Administration, 1938 (Box 80, Folder 29)
    - Neckwear Makers Union (United) 1935-37 (Box 80, Folder 30)
    - Negro Labor Committee (Frank Crosswaith) 1938 (Box 80, Folder 31)
    - Neibuhr, Reinhold (New York Labor War Chest) 1943, A history of the American Friends of German Freedom. (Box 80, Folder 32)
    - Neustadt, Richard, 1936 (Box 80, Folder 33)
    - Neville, W.P. (Labor) 1935 (Box 80, Folder 34)
    - New England Council on Economic Development and Research, 1938-39 (Box 80, Folder 35)
    - New Jersey Industrial Union Council, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - New Leader, 1936-37 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - New Masses, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - New Orleans Central Trades and Labor Council, 1935 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - New York City (correspondence with various city officials mostly from the Emergency Bureau of Relief) 1925-41 (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - New York City-Citizens Charter Campaign Committee, 1936, Why Labor Should Vote for the New City Charter and for Proportional Representation (8pp). (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - New York Clothing Cutters Union, 1940-41 (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - New York Clothing Manufacturers Exchange, 1937-40, Julius H. Levy's (Executive Secretary) request for assistance for his brother-in-law, Isidore Nassauer, who is interned in England. (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - New York Clothing Workers (appeal to Sidney Hillman) 1930 (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - New York State Federation of Labor, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - New York Fund, 1938-40 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - New York Joint Board, 1936-38 (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - New York Knee Pants, Inc., 1936 (Box 81, Folder 13)
    - New York League of Women Shoppers, 1938, "... helping the Metropolitan Industrial Agents in their fight for collective bargaining rights." (Box 81, Folder 14)
    - New York Post, 1939, Contains photographs of the model of the Textile Building to be constructed for the 1939 New York World's Fair. (Box 81, Folder 15)
    - New Republic, 1936, Bruce Bliven's (editor) recommendation that Hillman bring a libel suit against W.R. Hearst. (Box 81, Folder 16)
    - New School for Social Research, 1936-37 (Box 81, Folder 17)
    - New York State (correspondence with representatives of the Governors Office, Dept. of Labor and Labor Relations Board) 1935-40 (Box 81, Folder 18)
    - New York State Commission on Public Housing, 1938-40 (Box 81, Folder 19)
    - New York State Constitutional Convention Committee, 1938 (Box 81, Folder 20)
    - New York State Labor Committee, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 21)
    - New York State Industrial Union Council, 1940 (Box 81, Folder 22)
    - News (United States) 1938 (Box 81, Folder 23)
    - New Zionist Organization of America, 1945 (Box 81, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper Guild (American) 1936-40 (Box 81, Folder 25)
    - Nollsch, Henry, 1936 (Box 81, Folder 26)
    - Non-Sectarian Anti-Nazi League, 1935-41, Support for the withdrawal of American athletes from the 1936 Berlin Olympics. (Box 81, Folder 27)
    - Norris, George, 1941 (Box 81, Folder 28)
    - Novik, Morris (Radio WEVD, NYC) 1935 (Box 81, Folder 29)
    - Nowogrodsky, Emanuel (American Representative of the General Jewish Workers in Poland) 1941, Obtaining visas for the family of Henrich Erlich (leader of the Jewish labor movement in Poland ("Bund"), and editor of Poland's Jewish daily newspaper (Naje Folkscajtung). (Box 81, Folder 30)
    - Null, Samuel (1938) concerning agreement and Dept. Store Workers Organizing Committee, Agreement with Gimble Brothers, Inc. (Box 81, Folder 31)